naturesway.com 2019-05-30

# Privacy Policy - Nature's Way®.

###  Schwabe North America, Inc. - Website Privacy Policy  
_Last Modified: February 28, 2018_

This Privacy Policy applies to the websites, social media pages, mobile applications, widgets or online services that are owned or controlled by Schwabe North America, Inc. and its subsidiaries (collectively, “Schwabe North America” or “we” or “us”) and that post a link to this Privacy Policy (collectively, “Sites,” and individually, a “Site”). This Privacy Policy only covers information collected at the Sites and does not cover any information collected at any other web site or offline by Schwabe North America (unless specifically stated). This Privacy Policy describes Schwabe North America ’s information collection practices at the Sites, such as the types of information Schwabe North America collects regarding visitors to the Sites and how we may use that information.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to any other website owned or operated by any third party even if such third party links to a Site or if Schwabe North America links to that third party website. Accordingly, this Privacy Policy does not apply to the practices of any third party or business partner that Schwabe North America does not own or control.

####  1\. YOUR CONSENT

Please review this Policy before using the Site. By using this Site, you are consenting to the collection, use and disclosure of your information as set forth in this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to be bound by this Privacy Policy, you may not access or use the Sites.

####  2\. DEFINITIONS

For purposes of this Privacy Policy:

  * **“Aggregate Information”** means information about groups or categories of data, which does not identify and cannot reasonably be used to identify an individual, such as web traffic analytics.
  * **“Anonymous Information”** means information that does not directly or indirectly identify, and cannot reasonably be used to identify, an individual, such as Cookies.
  * **“Cookies”** means anonymous, unique identifiers that a website places on the hard drive of your computer or mobile device when you visit the website.  Cookies may involve the transmission of information from us to you and from you directly to us, to another party on our behalf, or to another party in accordance with its Privacy Policy.
  * **“Flash  Cookies”** means local shared objects that are used to store personalized information based on visits to websites.
  * **“Personal Information”** means information that identifies (whether directly or indirectly) an individual, such as the individual’s name, postal address, email address or telephone number. When Anonymous Information is directly or indirectly associated with Personal Information, this Anonymous Information also is treated as Personal Information.
  * **“Web Beacons”** means small pieces of data that are embedded in images on the pages of Sites. Web beacons may involve the transmission of information directly to us, to another party on our behalf, or to another party in accordance with its Privacy Policy.

####  3\. COLLECTION OF INFORMATION

We collect two basic types of information from you and about you – Personal Information and Anonymous Information. We may use Personal and Anonymous Information to create a third type of information – Aggregate Information. For example, we collect contact information, demographic information, purchasing information, information you submit or post, and payment information. If you use our Sites, we may collect information about the browser you’re using or other traffic information.

We collect information in different ways. We collect information that you give to us. For example, if you register with us, contact us for information, or participate in a promotion.

We collect information about you automatically. Where permitted by law we use tracking tools such as browser Cookies and Web Beacons to collect information from you. We collect information about users over time when you use the Sites. We collect information about you from third parties, such as social media platforms and advertising analytics providers. We may have third parties collect information as described in this Privacy Policy, for example in Section 6.

####  4\. USE OF INFORMATION

We use information that we collect including Personal Information for a variety of purposes. We use information to respond to your requests or questions. We use information to improve our Sites, products, programs and services. We might use your information to customize your experience with us.

We use information to administer our Site and for internal operations. For example, we may aggregate or anonymize your information for analytics, research or other business purposes. We combine information. For example, we may combine information that we have collected offline with information we collect online, to the extent permitted by law, for the transactional purpose, or by your consent. We may combine information we get from you with information about you we get from third parties.

We use information for security purposes. Where legally permitted, we may use your information to protect our company, our customers, and our websites.

We use information for marketing purposes. For example, we might send you information about new products or services or special offers. We might also use your information to serve you ads about our products, services and offers. We might tell you about new features or updates. These might be third-party offers or products we think you might find interesting. If you register with us, we’ll send you our promotional emails.

We use information to communicate with you about your account, purchases or our relationship. We may contact you about your account or for feedback. We might also contact you about this Privacy Policy or our Site Usage Terms and Conditions.

We use information to comply with applicable law, and as otherwise permitted by applicable law.

####  5\. DISCLOSURE AND SHARING OF INFORMATION.

We may use third party service providers to perform certain services on behalf of the Sites, such as web site hosting, accepting job applications, providing web site usage analytics, sending email or other communications, providing marketing assistance and data analysis, providing consumer affairs services, fulfilling and processing orders, or performing other administrative services. We may provide these service providers with access to your Personal Information so that they can carry out the services they are performing for you or for Schwabe North America. Some of these service providers may collect information on the Sites directly from you on our behalf; in such cases, these service providers are not permitted to use your Personal Information for their own use.

You may be presented with an opportunity to receive information and/or marketing offers from one or more third parties. If you agree at that time to have your Personal Information shared, your Personal Information will be disclosed to that third party (or parties) and will be subject to the privacy policy and practices of that third party. We are not responsible for the privacy policies and practices of third parties, and, if you later decide that you no longer want to receive communications from a third party, you will need to contact that third party directly. You also may request, sometimes through your use of an interactive feature or third party application, that we share information about you with a third party, and we will typically do so under those circumstances.

We may offer sweepstakes, contests, and other promotions (collectively, a “Promotion”) that may require registration. By participating in a Promotion, you are agreeing to the official rules that govern that Promotion, which may contain specific requirements of you, including, except where prohibited by law, allowing the sponsor(s) of the Promotion to use your name, voice, likeness or other indicia of persona in advertising or marketing associated with the Promotion. If you choose to enter a Promotion, your Personal Information may be disclosed to third parties or the public in connection with the administration of such Promotion, including, without limitation, in connection with winner selection, prize fulfillment, and as required by law or permitted by the Promotion's official rules, such as on a winners list.

We may also disclose your Personal Information: i) as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process; ii) when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request; or iii) if Schwabe North America is involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of its assets.

####  6\. COOKIES AND OTHER TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES

We collect information, and authorize our third party vendors to collect information, about users over time across our Sites and for other services. To do this, we and/or our third party vendors use several common tracking tools. These may include Cookies, Web Beacons, Flash Cookies, and similar technologies.

We may use these cookies and tracking technologies:

To recognize new or past customers.

  * To store your password if you are registered to our Site.
  * To improve our Sites.
  * To serve you with interest-based or targeted advertising
  * To observe your behaviors and browsing activities over time across multiple websites or other platforms.
  * To better understand the interests of our customers and our Site visitors.
  * In connection with an email delivery and marketing company to send emails that you have agreed to receive. Pixel tags and cookies are used in those email messages and at our Site to help us measure the effectiveness of our advertising, how our visitors use our Site and to enable us to provide more focused and subsequent email marketing communications to you.

Some content or applications, including advertisements, on the Site are served by third-parties, including advertisers, ad networks and servers, content providers, and application providers. These third parties may use cookies alone or in conjunction with Web Beacons or other tracking technologies to collect information about you when you use our Site. The information they collect may be associated with your online activities over time and across different websites and other online services. They may use this information to provide you with interest-based (behavioral) advertising or other targeted content, which is often referred to as remarketing.

While we may use a variety of service providers to perform advertising services, some of these companies are members of the Network Advertising Initiative (“NAI”) or the Digital Advertising Alliance ("DAA") Self-Regulatory Program for Online Behavioral Advertising. You may want to visit <http://www.networkadvertising.org/managing/opt_out.asp>, which provides information regarding targeted advertising and the “opt-out” procedures of NAI members. You may also want to visit <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>, which provides information regarding targeted advertising and offers an “opt-out” by participating companies in the DAA Self-Regulatory Program. Please note that these companies may still collect information when you are online and opting out through these mechanisms does not opt you out of being served advertising. You will continue to receive generic ads while visiting the Sites and elsewhere online.

####  7\. DO NOT TRACK DISCLOSURES

At this time, there are no worldwide uniform or consistent industry standards or definition for responding to, processing, or communicating "Do Not Track" signals. As a result, the Site is unable to respond to "Do Not Track" signals. You can refer to the instructions in your browser to make sure the appropriate settings are selected, and to set your preferences with respect to "Do Not Track" signals.

####  8\. SECURITY AND RETENTION

Schwabe North America has reasonable technical and organizational security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse or alteration of information under our control. However, Schwabe North America cannot guarantee that unauthorized third parties will never be able to defeat those security measures. Although we cannot guarantee that our systems are 100% secure 100% of the time, we periodically update our technology in order to improve the protection of customer information.

We retain personal information as long as it is necessary or relevant for the practices described in this Privacy Policy. We also keep information as otherwise required or permitted by law.

####  9\. WE STORE INFORMATION BOTH IN AND OUTSIDE OF THE U.S.

Information we collect from you may be transferred to, or stored at, a destination in the United States or another destination outside of United States. It may be processed by staff operating in these locations who work for us or for one of our suppliers. Such staff may be engaged in, among other things, the processing of your payment details and the provision of support services. If you live outside of the United States, you understand and agree that we may transfer your information to the United States. U.S. laws may not afford the same level or protection as those in your country.

####  10\. GOVERNING LAW AND JURISDICTION

This Privacy Policy, and Schwabe North America's collection and use of customer information, shall be governed and interpreted in accordance with the laws of the United States and the State of Wisconsin. Any disputes arising out of this Privacy Policy shall be adjudicated in Milwaukee County, Wisconsin or a federal court of competent jurisdiction in the Eastern District of the State of Wisconsin.

####  11\. GOVERNING LANGUAGE

Any translation of this Privacy Policy is done for local requirements and in the event of a dispute between the English and any non-English versions, the English version of this Privacy Policy shall govern.

####  12\. CHANGES TO PRIVACY POLICY

Schwabe North America may make changes to this statement from time to time. We will post changes to our Privacy Policy here, so be sure to check back periodically.

####  13\. HOW TO ACCESS AND MODIFY PERSONAL INFORMATION

We provide you the ability to exercise certain controls and choices regarding our collection, use and sharing of your information.

You may request that we correct, update and delete your account by contacting us at privacyquestion@naturesway.com or by writing to us at Schwabe North America Customer Service at 825 Challenger Drive, Green Bay, WI 54311.

You may unsubscribe from receiving offers and promotions for our products and services through the unsubscribe mechanisms provided in our promotional communications. Even if you opt out of getting marketing messages, we will send you transactional messages. These include responses to your questions.

####  14\. QUESTIONS, COMMENTS, CONCERNS

If you have any questions or comments about our use of Personal Information or about this Privacy Policy, please contact us at privacyquestion@naturesway.com. Schwabe North America will use reasonable efforts to promptly investigate any complaint you may have regarding our use of Personal Information and to comply fully with the legal and regulatory supervisory authorities responsible.

####  15\. OUR SITES AND CHILDREN

Our Sites where this Privacy Policy is found are meant for adults. We do not knowingly collect Personal Information from children under 18 without permission from a parent or guardian. If you are a parent or legal guardian and think your child under 18 has given us information, you can contact us at privacyquestion@naturesway.com, or write to us at Customer Service at 825 Challenger Drive, Green Bay, WI 54311. Please mark your inquiries "COPPA Information Request." Parents in the United States, you can learn more about how to protect children's privacy on-line at [www.consumer.ftc.gov/articles/0031-protecting-your-childs-privacy-online](https://www.consumer.ftc.gov/articles/0031-protecting-your-childs-privacy-online).

####  16\. YOUR CALIFORNIA PRIVACY RIGHTS

If you reside in California, you have the right to ask us one time each year if we have shared personal information with third parties for their direct marketing purposes. To make a request, please send us an email at privacyquestion@naturesway.com or write to us at the address listed below. Indicate in your letter that you are a California resident making a "Shine the Light" inquiry.
